Okay, we're going to call the Board of the Reggers, the Prime Minister of Council meeting for today's
day and time.
I don't choose public input, no scheduled personal parenthesis, anyone else who wishes to address
the council on any council agenda issues?
I don't three as a consent agenda staff is recommending that items full of advice, which are
flames and minutes again for the approval for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on those items, then there are a tank of ocean to approve as recommended.
Second, second, roll call?
Orkin?
Lewis, aye.
Weston.
Short.
Item six is a public hearing on the executive, so the USDA grant to purchase equipment.
I saw some communication amount of $50,000 per answer.
Yes, if you'd like, before the public hearing, we'd be more than happy to go with that.
Glent can not be here tonight.
Okay.
But there is, we have been notified that we're eligible for a $50,000 USDA grant.
Now, this is a 35-65-split grant.
The USDA funding will pay for $35,000.
The total projects are about $25,000 in their various equipment.
Number of it for a 911 center for our dispatchers and also for a generator.
We have some items for utilities, for our wine group, and I'm trying to remember offhand with the other items.
But they're basically items we had in our budget.
And by receiving this grant, basically, we're getting a 35% discount.
I think that's the spoke to us about this several months ago before she applied, correct?
And I think it kind of went through the items in.
And that's exactly what going to does for us when we have these needs.
She just basically scours every place you can find to get a grant funds to be able to go with this.
And she's doing a terrific job.
Again, this is basically a $50,000 grant for items that we need anyway.
And it will reduce the cost of taxpayers and rate payers.
Okay? So this is a public hearing on the grant.
If there's anyone that wishes to make any comments, they should do so now.
They're being known. I'm going to close the public hearing.
And we're going to move on to item seven, which is to accept or reject the USDA grant agreement.
And let our conditions of purchasing equipment and up from the resolution.
And again, Glenn, there's not here in the height.
But what would you be able to put up the VA please?
And I think the list is in the VA.
Put up the VA so we can take a look at the list very quickly.
There it is. So we have the dispatch equipment, the Interruptible Power Supply,
and GA, our Cemetery, the Co-Bone and Traktor, Solid Ways.
We have John Deere of the Lens, and then Public Utilities, the Mini-Direct.
So that the total of them.
We'll do the main one on Saturday 9 and have the bowl be on Sunday afternoon.
And in your packet it's got the dates highlighted.
So you guys can kind of see that.
That's what we would be looking at.
If we did move forward in 2020 it would be December 6th.
And then 2021 it would be December 5th and 2022 it would be December 4th.
May you be questions for Amanda?
She's just basically asking for us to approve her submitting the bid.
Can we continue on the naming sponsors agreeing to three year commitment also?
I mean the year sponsorship.
You can't get them from these two entities when we look elsewhere.
Is that okay?
I've made calls and I just only so much money in the community and it's very tough right now.
We're trying to sell them out and trying to sell ads.
And I can tell you that even getting people to do $250 for an ad right now is it's tough.
So in 20,000 dollars it's a lot of money.
I mean you can look at the statistics on the economic impact.
I mean it's their name.
I mean down to her resort.
It's all over the national on a level that it's a good buy for them.
It's a good use of their products.
I'm hopeful.
I mean I mean I mean I should provide a bit of people that's on their business committee.
They call it that questions that you still don't until they get that brand.
I don't know which way I look at this.
I don't know if anybody else right now that we're making it into this.
The two of their outlets that we've got like for the possibility and that's where we got shot in quite so.
This is kind of this kind of bit of something get them on board and over and forth.
I mean it's just this it's a big risk for us and I would have a hard time coming.
You guys need to come to Dean to say we think we can try to sell enough tickets to cover it.
It's just such a huge.
With the weather the time of year is you don't know how the crowd's going to be.
We wouldn't have to have that $20,000 to be able to produce the amount.
Unless you have the idea that's the only thing that you can do.
So we can back I mean we can back out if we had to I mean before with the bid and then we don't get sponsorships.
We can we could it's kind of round up on I mean it's kind of when you submit it to the national office.
They want to get out of here.
That's what I want you to ask that question because we came up with a CD meeting as well.
So.
So Amanda had do had.
In the second third year was it pretty automatic that those entities.
Came up with the $20,000 that you have to go to them and say.
When we first met with them they made the three year agreement.
Okay.
So if you feel comfortable if they do that again that they're not going to change their mind in the year two or three.
long as we deliver the product, the same product we've been delivered.
Any other questions?
Do we have a motion to approve the submission?
The submission of the intention?
Can the intention of on give you the bold answer?
I'll make a motion.
We have a second.
I can.
Will call please?
Louis, I work at Western.
Hi.
So.
I don't care about getting a recreational field rental agreement.
Chop, give them an end.
Okay.
So, as we continue to grow, especially in sports, starting tourism in the world,
and more outside birds and things that we wanted to use in our facilities,
we wanted to take a look at our agreement with the current,
to have a safe, for a reason that we need to stop today.
And there's a couple of things.
And so, as a staff, a few things that we looked at
was, I did a lot of research with the higher cities,
and other municipalities on what they do,
as far as the third city fields and how much they charge,
and things like that, and stipulations that they offer.
And so, when I brought that all back to our staff to go over,
one of the things I've noticed was to actual rental field cell.
The agreement currently says it's 125 hours per field per day.
And there's also a lot of them in there for lights.
There's $20 in there.
And they live in a safe, per field, or anything like that,
and it's basically $20 in there.
So, what we're suggesting is basically a change in that rate to 125 to 150 per field.
And that will take care of the cost of the lights as well.
It makes a little bit cleaner.
You're still going to fall in because we don't have to just have many lights.
It's kind of hours to use the lights for it.
The next thing that we asked was the language for the payment.
The current agreement has an entity.
An entity is needed to cut it in full, 14 days in advance before the actual event.
The tournament world, that's pretty hard to determine how many actually fields that we're using.
So, what we have is three days prior to the event.
They will pay 50% of the lowest total of the invoice.
And then the next, the remainder of the invoice will be due.
The next following business day by five, five, five, five, five.
You wish to take a play on Monday.
And the third and final one was the language for the weather condition conditions.
Basically, it gives an innocent official that is, you know,
on duty or out about.
is that there's weather in the area or there's people going to be in danger.
This basically gives them the authority to basically shut that down.
That way they can everybody just say to be at an issue where a situation in May,
where we city had a turn to go on, baseball turn to go on at the weekend.
We had four gig baseball teams in the town, and we had an outside bird print in the
middle of the city.
This grid was written in the fields for mass.
It worked really well with us.
The man that no one had seen in the top of the park to make sure that everybody was safe.
But the most important thing in there is to say that the city officials have authority
to shut that down and make sure everybody is safe.
We wanted to add that language in there as well.
You're saying any city employee or we need to desolate.
The department had the list of it.
But the way it's worried is, it's suffocated in legislation by any city official
a police officer or a proper authorized agent of the city and mine on the termination of the
violation of the code or time to declare emergencies.
And the event of people make weather conditions.
The other, to go back to point two, we're so Amanda and the CVV had a situation.
I don't think that you guys were involved, but the football guy was put on the football
not turning them into whatever you want to call it.
And we struggled to get payment from the trust authority.
And so are you getting much pushed back right?
Or is the push back you're getting right now on the 14 days, simply because they generally don't know
what their registration is going to be because they may have a 10 day deadline or something.
And I've raised that point to say, I would feel more comfortable if you still require it.
Even if it was three days, but you required all of it three days in advance.
Because then the foundation no by then.
And then you're not chasing anybody afterwards.
You're always dealing with reputable people, then you don't have any problems.
But if you run into one like we ran into, then you could have half of your money outstanding.
And maybe 75% is the number, you know, in 25% after.
I just, that doesn't happen.
Often because of that experience we had it makes me a little anxious to let them pay after.
If they're already used to paying ahead of time.
And if our prices are value anyway, which it sounds like they are.
This is usually, like right now, 14 days in advance.
They're deadline to enter the tournament isn't until the three days ahead.
like on Wednesday, when he does turn into a city on Wednesday's
the kettle, so Wednesday, he does, he'll start cracking.
Well, like, Chad Ross from Fairland, we work closely with him.
Fairland athletic, for instance, the city facilities
a lot from fundraiser.
Well, they, they're not going to end up 14 days in advance
whether they need two bills or whether they need all five bills.
So that's what we were running into.
We just, we wanted to clean the language up a little bit.
I mean, basically we're talking about him.
We're talking about a couple of other local organizations.
And to be honest with you, most of them take the money from their gates.
It's how they do their turn into some working.
We're getting the money that they collect from the gates.
So what, then, what would you estimate the exposure of the gate?
You know, what is it, what is it, what is it, I mean,
five bills or five days, what we're talking about,
for three days, $2,000 total, and so 50% of that would be a thousand.
That would be the exposure of the, those approximate numbers.
Yeah, I mean, roughly once you see average rate and for a weekend, it's two days.
And you would see Mark from two to four bills of $2,000.
Most of the ground is totally bad at the past, that's what we're supposed to do.
And you can always adopt the policy you're recommending,
and if you get barred at time or two, or you visit that.
If you're doing people with like, if you're doing business, people are fairly in all of you,
you have a high degree of confidence in them.
It's really these people that are coming completely outside the community,
you don't have to turn it about.
Any other questions or concerns?
So staff is asking us to approve the recreational field role and
remet that Chuck has kind of described the three changes to.
Do you want to implement that?
We have a motion to approve.
I'll make motion.
Yeah, second.
Second it.
We'll call.
My student.
Hi.
Lewis, I have four kids.
Chuck, you're up next again.
I don't know that.
I'm going to demo use for use of city facilities for sports and recreation,
pinning this submission of insurance and food and transportation.
Specifically, the Northeast Oklahoma soccer Association and youth development
foundation for flag control.
So yes, we, at that time of year, we start from three or two employees and give them up
and get them signed.
So the ones that we just mentioned, we have a friend here tonight for local soccer.
Local soccer for lady and the new flag to bully.
So again, staff can together.
Look at the M.O.U.S. and this is myself, Amanda, and I'm here tonight, Captain Browning and Justin
Elgin Hurt, and I'm going to notice this.
So if you've heard a few things that we want to look at and change, number one is the season.
These, you know, these in the past have been basically a full fiscal year.
I would be glad I would want to June 3rd it.
Well, we're looking at the deal, and it's changed up to the actual season of winter actually,
you can play.
This just makes everything look cleaner for us in the city and who has the rights to build that
jitter time.
It helps us scheduling things like that for city tournaments that we put on.
The other one we want to do, you know?
I think that's you.
Yeah.
Sorry.
The second one was, they had a language to be added to the, you know, in my news, we're making the city
and any other authorized users that they're complex to use their clients.
So a lot of these facilities, the sessions things in general are had their equipment, they're
talking about the leading itself, not a lot of city equipment inside accessions things.
So I'm actually a season zone with, you know, in the past, we were there using it or somebody
bringing to facility and used it in the wasn't anything going to protect anybody from the actual
appliances that are there for on the lead.
So this gives the actual the lead the options to either fall or shut it out, tap machines
or with or if they're on the lead bit that just lets us use that.
And then it also says that for this, for use by city in the authorized users and that the city
should not be responsible for anything just during or after the tournament.
The third recommendation is scheduling.
If they're, and I usually, from a city standpoint, general tournaments will try not to do this,
but scheduling tournaments during their actual season.
Try not to disrupt them too much, but sometimes they kind of overlap.
And especially in baseball and softball, when scheduling tournaments.
And what I used to try to do is give them ample time of, hey, they're using the city events.
I'm looking for what they can put their schedule out.
But adding black updates.
What set those gives city staff time on that to say, for example, a Saturday sun.
The Friday before, no activities on the fields, no practice, no vans from the late,
is us in a partial partner, that she has to feel very, and then on Monday,
based on clean up day, the Spector temperature,
at the beginning of the order, before we hand it back off, too.
So we're asking for, based on what we call blackout dates,
the day before the day after.
The next one is blackout dates, seed dates.
Chuck and Amanda, the CVB is reviewed all this already.
The CVB and the second one is recommended to you guys.
Any questions or concerns from Chuck or Amanda?
Which is the flag football player?
Well, I'm kind of giving it a brief summary of this new lead that's been formed.
So we have a group of people in down there, that's very new,
a realization.
And it's YADF, which stands for Youth Athletic Development Foundation.
Well, they'd be in direct competition with the other football teams, the blue and the gold.
No, I met with the Brian Jotto as the president of this white, white, white, YADF.
Also, the president of my youth football, I'm burning around it.
And they've actually worked together on this.
They both felt like they were still in players.
Black, silver, black football.
The numbers this year for youth football, and then the tackle side.
I'm not sure what Brian's goal was for black football.
But I did see that he has 10 spots left open.
I'm actually going to be the 10 next week, and I'd like to know what that number is.
He's kind of fine on half.
But I know it's from ages five to eleven years old is what he's offering.
But that's what Melix came out.
Yes, it is.
It is covered.
And they will be sharing same with those soccer drumplots.
And Brian, it's also met with John Olin, which is the soccer of the president.
He actually ran a child about to one of the four beatings in the Senate.
The plan of our his vision of black football had same way else.
And they all felt like they should be an issue with our schedule.
I was concerned.
I think a lot of the black football football games itself.
I don't know if I was on the airplane.
So I'll be using it myself.
It's the hard work that's here just for practices, concerns, so there's been an overlapping with that.
Also, this YADF is also going to be taken over the local wreck, use the basketball,
and you're in about the most impressive.
Yeah, are there any interest in the surrounding communities for the flag football?
Yeah, they've heard much advertising from the county standpoint,
and I've never heard a few people that I know personally in my circle,
that are living up the towns that have to come over and sign up to play.
I know our neighbor and town commerce that y'all would apply football.
But some of these other smaller towns like your actions and your projects.
Well, they don't have enough for football team anyway, so.
I'm a very, very, very little bit, so.
Well, I'm a very, very, very kind of a step up, obviously, for the new basketball standpoint,
and I'm actually to see how.
And I've been in a few occasions, Brian, for the first four months about this,
and there's a lot of things that you've just got going on and so.
One of the questions, are they going to be self-funding?
Of course, the city expected to come up with any revenue for all of them to be taken care of.
They just, um, you know, revenue from registrations and things like that.
They are. This year they're not going to do any concessions.
So, I think they're just going to have, um, like 90% of sales and stuff like that.
They're going to revenue.
All right.
They'll be using the city facility, the gym for the basketball.
Yes, yes.
Yes.
Your contribution is you, you're allowing them to use the civic center and the service to the community.
Which one did for years and years?
And then, I think, for year or two, the Boston Hills Club have the program at their facility.
So, I think it's good that it's back here.
But it's just a better facility than we're all going to have for the government.
I understand why they did what they did, but this is a better facility for the kids.
Okay.
Any other questions?
If not, we have a motion to approve the, uh, to the MOU's,
the one with both East O'Police on Association and the one with the Youth Development Foundation.
Sorry.
Second, roll call, please.
Work it.
All right.
Weston.
Through this, I chose.
Thanks, Chuck.
I'm 12.
There's nomination of Charlotte Halder, a place to give the award as a 29 key representative of the
Grand Gateway Board of Directors to complete the unexpected turn.
I'm making that nomination for your consideration.
I'll say that.
So, she's got her first.
Second, I got her.
Ow, okay.
Sorry, well co-placed.
Lewis, I was still working.
All right.
OK, thank you.
Item 13 is temporary road closure.
On 20th anniversary of over these, between B and C,
to allow Washington School to make the one-way
shattering at the beginning of the school.
We've done several schools, Roosevelt, Wilson,
and Rockdale, all use Barricades to make a one-way
and from the school.
I lost the tax.
I didn't remember at the end of the year, last year.
We ran for 40 days, 40 nights after that.
But, honestly, I just got to go to this agenda.
School starts tomorrow, so they're one, two,
make sure they're there.
I love to do this.
They're just schools on their Barricades.
They're one-way and they're one-way.
And just make a circle for kids to pick up after school.
And that's the same procedure we've used it.
I know at least three of the other elementary schools,
I'm not sure about the fourth one, but it's standard.
It works really well for Rebecca and makes a circle for kids.
We did that at Washington before.
Yeah.
We did it close to Washington before.
I agree.
OK.
That's when I was there.
We did that.
Well, now we want a group.
A group.
We can go back into the minutes and look.
We can't even.
Yes, I'll make a motion.
Do you have to go to a red-close your eyes?
Second.
Red-close?
Loosed?
Yes.
Or could I?
So?
I'm 14, except a rejected agreement and a true redelation
with the Oklahoma Department of Art and Transportation
for the mainstream improvements.
This has been our long-awaited item, Sean.
This is the last.
OK.
Once they get this e-green in fact, they will do a requisition
for federal funds, that's approval to actually bid this thing.
Okay.
Did we need any discussion?
Or would you just want to move on with a motion?
Move forward.
And the motion?
Yes.
Second.
It's because it's a great rock.
OK.
I'm going to try and get to Bobby before the whole thing is going to happen.
That's how it's going to last thing then, Biggie, get out of the red line.
You're basically going to have to hold off for what we did before.
Right.
This is much more comprehensive and covers a lot of issues that were not addressed in our previous
ordinance.
And we have a timeframe constraint in that this has to be approved by September 13th.
Not only by you all, but also by FEMA and open a lot of resources board.
So we're going to apologize this again.
Because you need me all saying, you guys have to prove your thing.
I can't.
I don't know what the city is on that list too much.
No, no.
I don't know.
I will say this though, Biggie, that.
So you have a copy in front of me now and it changes that we make to it based on the meeting
that we have next week at home Tuesday.
Then we can.
OK.
I just didn't know if you're a wrist line of that showing you what changes those are.
But this is completely.
OK.
It's very, very, very different than what we're going to do.
And it's just model after the whole city.
It's been a place for a while.
I think it's, it's worked very well for that.
OK.
Hi.
Anybody want to delve into this at all an hour or two on this, read it between now or two.
I'd like to talk to you.
Yeah.
We intend to make a presentation on it as our next.
OK.
So thank you.
Christy, item 16.
Christy is, if you want to prove a lot split at property of property, I want to wonder.
Can you find a way we go earth in each exhibit, is it it we?
Be.
I don't know.
Just to give you guys why you exactly where it's at.
Thank you, please.
So this is a lot that we're talking about right off of Main Street.
More than the two two and south of the Chinese.
It's currently full of holding buildings.
OK.
And there's a snow cone.
Yep.
On it.
Awesome.
So that's a lot split that's been presented to us for consideration.
And it meets all zoning.
The proposed use meets zoning and all that stuff.
It's a commercial zoning right now.
There are still questions that I mean, they haven't presented us with any of the details on the design of the building and all of that.
So in here.
They're supposed to also address whether or not the water and sewage supply is sufficient.
We don't know till we know what they're actually intending to build, but most likely is.
I guess that it's not required, but the same issue would be for electric.
I'm assuming we don't need to have any additional infrastructure because of what their plans are.
So the rumor without naming names is a restaurant.
I would assume that they would have adequate sewage.
If they've been a business area that we have targeted for redevelopment, we will want to help.
That's much as possible with that.
Again, we now have actually this will create two lots for new development on Main Street.
It's pretty exciting.
So which lot are they going to use the north of the south?
One right next to the north is also being looked at for additional development as well.
I don't know exactly what, but I do know there are people looking at it for development.
I hope for Texas Roadhouse.
Keep open, right?
I think it's excellent.
You're right.
Spitting that half is going to help.
The other half is going to help.
Are there any other questions?
Staff is working with the perspective development owner on their ideas, and they're going to have to meet all code and do all the things they have to do.
But it will be new construction in an area that can certainly benefit.
What's that zone now?
It's commercial and C.
It's commercial.
That was being proposed.
It needs to be done.
It's going to be hard.
Sounds good?
So why don't we even have to vote on a lot split?
Well.
Your code requires it.
Yes.
Well, you are acting as the plan zone information.
Now I'll try.
I forgot to bring that out.
Any other questions?
If there aren't on, do we have a motion to approve the law split?
So, and a second statement?
We'll call please.
Or get?
Louis?
I was.
Hi.
Seventeen is a mayor's nomination to appoint sir on the quick to the land, the recreation, tourism, convention, and business.
We're going to be really advisory board with placing Steve Gilbert.
Amanda?
I think sir, does she already?
What is he?
They are in the mine.
Right.
And we'll be sure best.
Because we're going to expect to have a two hotel representative on that board.
Right now we just have more than that representative.
Okay.
So, Amanda's suggestion, I have nominated Sarah McWig to serve on that board and for your approval.
So, I would need a motion.
Motion to approve.
And a second.
Second.
roll call for this.
Western.
All right.
We will have a second.
Thank you, everyone.
Either making this new business, or any business,
a residence is the question.
19.
Staff reports.
Staff's available.
If you have questions.
20 is mayor and council committee announcements.
Any announcements?
Anyone?
We are meeting next Tuesday.
We are.
Member.
For 30.
To the manager.
Communication.
Thank you.
In the study session.
That's just what I wanted to talk about.
We have the flood ordinance that you just received.
We also have a new ordinance for guarding.
For 41.
And the district and streets.
That we would like us to see.
And also an anti solicitation ordinance.
So, give them more.
We will be discussing.
And the fourth item is a police cadet program.
This can develop by our police department.
It is really pretty interesting.
Through the evening creation.
About that as well.
So, that's our study session.
That's on report.
Item 22 is meeting the big and tangerine from council chambers.
and we can be in a meeting room one for courses of the executive session.
And I have how long do I want to take?
Five minutes, three minutes.
We will be coming back.
So I want to go home.
Let's hear it all.
Everybody gets in there.
I'm meeting three minutes later.